## **Todd Evans**

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Melbourne, VIC

**J** 0438 99 0438

evansmtodd@gmail.com

github.com/tomiev

in @todd-evans-te

#### **PROFILE**

Software developer who loves working with others, problemsolving and learning new skills. I transitioned to coding when I realised that the programming aspect of my psychology research was what I enjoyed the most.

With my background in psychology and people-focused job experiences, I'm a natural team player who cares about my peers and performs well in collaborative teams.

#### **TECH STACK**

JavaScript, HTML/CSS, REST API, PostgreSQL, Git & GitHub, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, Heroku, UX/UI design on Figma. Currently learning React.

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Eagerness to learn, teamoriented, able to work autonomously, creativity, resilience

# HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Basketball, bouldering / rock climbing, guitar

## **MOST RECENT PROJECTS**

ChurnIt

JavaScript • Ruby on Rails • HTML5 • CSS3 •

Bootstrap • Heroku • Figma

ChurnIt helps users to find personalised credit card recommendations in seconds.

**LearnIt** 

Ruby on Rails  $\bullet$  JavaScript  $\bullet$  HTML5  $\bullet$  CSS3  $\bullet$ 

Bootstrap • Heroku • Figma

LearnIt is a web app for posting and finding online tutoring sessions.

## **WORK HISTORY**

## **English as a Second Language Tutor**

Self-Employed

Feb 2021 - Mar 2022

- Independently planned and taught culturally appropriate (and fun!) ESL lessons via Zoom to primary school and adult students living in China.
- All three of my primary school students scored 100% on their end-of-term English examinations in 2022.

## **Disability Support Worker**

Private

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

• As sole carer on each shift, worked autonomously to provide empathetic support to a client living with an intellectual disability.

#### Bartender / Café Assistant

Vela 9 Inverloch

Nov 2018 - Mar 2021

 Working as part of a dynamic hospitality team, I provided excellent customer service in a fast-paced café.

## **EDUCATION HISTORY**

## Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Le Wagon Melbourne

Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

Ten-week full-time course focussing on Javascript, Ruby on Rails, CSS, HTML, SQL, and UX/UI design.

## Bachelor of Arts (Psychology) (Hons.)

Monash University

Feb 2017 - Nov 2021